usagym.org 2019-04-24

# USA Gymnastics | Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for USA Gymnastics’ web pages, blogs, mobile applications, and other interactive content; collectively, our platform. 

It notifies you of the following: 

  1. What personally identifiable information is collected from you, how it is collected, how it is used, and with whom it may be shared.
  2. What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.
  3. The security procedures in place to protect against the misuse of your information.
  4. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

USA Gymnastics is the sole owner of the information collected on our platform. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily submit to us via online registration forms, email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone. 

We will use your information to respond to you regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request, e.g. to process a payment. 

USA Gymnastics collects information from our users at several points throughout our platform: 

**Membership Registration**  
To use our platform, a user must first complete the registration form. This could mean registering as a user and/or as a USA Gymnastics member. During either registration process, a user is required to give certain identifiable information such as: 
    * Your contact information [e.g. name, email address, mailing address, telephone number
    * Username and password
    * Demographic information [e.g. age, gender]
    * Communication preference
    * Correspondence and other information you send us
    * Additional information described at the point of collection
This information is used to contact you about the services in which you have expressed interest. This information is retained to facilitate your continued use of our platform, to register for events and educational courses, and to allow you to manage your account. 

**Event Registration**  
To register for an event, an entrant is required to give contact information such as name, address, phone number, and e-mail address, as well as information about his/her gymnastics abilities. We send this information about entrants to meet management personnel so they can properly and accurately prepare entry lists and conduct the event. 

**Newsletters**  
You may, upon occasion, receive electronic newsletters regarding USA Gymnastics information, member club updates, upcoming events, educational opportunities, etc. If you wish your email to be removed simply contact us via email at [membership@usagym.org](mailto:membership@usagym.org), or phone 800.345.4719. 

**Surveys**  
You may, upon occasion, receive satisfaction surveys regarding past events, congresses, member club inquiries, and/or other general gymnastics information. If you wish your email to be removed simply contact us via email at [membership@usagym.org](mailto:membership@usagym.org), or phone 800.345.4719. 

**Server Logs**  
We use standard server log files to analyze visitor trends, administer and troubleshoot our platforms, and gather technology statistics to help us improve. This information is not linked to personally identifiable information and is only used in the aggregate. 

**We use Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor's hard drive to help us improve your access and identify repeat visitors. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to log in using a password more than once, thereby saving time. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance your online experience. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information. 

We may allow third parties to place and read their own cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect information through the platform. For example, our third-party service providers may use these technologies to collect information that helps us with traffic measurements, research, and analytics. 

**Other Data Collection**  
We may collect information from people through other means by telephone, by e-mail, by fax, on paper, or in person. This privacy policy governs the use and disclosure of that information. 

You may contact us at any time by email [membership@usagym.org](mailto:membership@usagym.org), or by phone 800.345.4719: 

  * See what data we have about you, if any
  * Change/correct any data we have about you
  * Have us delete any data we have about you
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data

We contact platform users for various reasons. If you opt-in to receive contacts from us or our partners, you can change your mind later. If at any time, you would like to stop receiving such information or opt-out of a feature, you can let us know by sending an email stating your preference to [membership@usagym.org](mailto:membership@usagym.org) or by calling 800.345.4719. To help us address your request, please specify the feature from which you wish to top-out. You should be aware, however, that it is not always possible to completely remove or modify information in our databases and servers although we will always make reasonable efforts to do so upon your request. Some communications are required as a part of your membership with USA Gymnastics. 

In cases where USA Gymnastics collects personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18, we require parental consent before the collection is completed. For example, the USA Gymnastics membership application requires a parent's or guardian's signature before it will be accepted. The signature on the application evidences the parent's or guardian's consent to have the child's information used in accordance with this privacy policy. Upon request, a parent or guardian may obtain the information that his or her child has provided to USA Gymnastics; however, we can only verify the information [address, date of birth, etc.] 

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information, know that it is protected both online and offline. 

We operate entirely over a secure connection. Wherever we collect any information from users, that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for "https" at the beginning of the address on the web page, or by identifying the secure indicator's presence on your browser (usually a lock icon or green bar near the address bar). 

While we use encryption to protect all information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. 

We request information from you on our order form. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (like name and billing address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date, etc.) This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your order. If we have trouble processing an order, we'll use this information to contact you. Financial information is transmitted directly to a third-party payment processor, who employs industry-standard, PCI-compliant security and encryption. 

The platform contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave us to read the privacy statement of any other site that collects personally identifiable information. 

We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. 

We use an outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes beyond facilitating your order. 

At times, we may partner with another party to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. 

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time and all updates will be posted on this page. 

* * *

If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately via email at [membership@usagym.org](mailto:membership@usagym.org) or by phone at 800.345.4719. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact Cheryl Jarrett via email at [cjarrett@usagym.org](mailto:cjarrett@usagym.org) or by phone at 317.829.5625. 

﻿
